Guide to the photograph album Baba Gugur - First Oil Drilling in Iraq AD.MC.048
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- A portrait of a man holding a gun., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref40; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Iraq; Men; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Tents; Facial Hair; Weapons; Guns; Turbans; Petroleum industry and trade.
- A portrait of two men smoking in front of an automobile., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Group Portraits; Iraq; Smoking; Tobacco pipes; Cigarettes; Hats; Landscapes; Petroleum industry and trade.
- A man smoking a pipe with camels grazing in the background., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref42; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Iraq; Petroleum industry and trade.; Men; Water; Camels; Animals; Guns; Weapons; Tobacco pipes; Smoking
- Views of a village and a bridge over a river (likely to be the Little Zab River)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref43; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Great Zab River; Kirkuk Governorate, Iraq; Bridges; Architecture; Buildings; Little Zab River; Rivers
- A portrait of a man repairing a car tire., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref44; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Guns; Weapons; Workers; Iraq; Petroleum industry and trade.
- The Temple of Baalshamin, Palmyra., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref45; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Temples; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- The village of Tadmur and archway of the Temple of Bel, Palmyra., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref46; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Houses; Men; Regional/National Dress
- Palmyra, possibly Palmyra Castle (Fakhr-al-Din al-Ma'ani)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref47; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles
- Colonnaded street, Palmyra., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref48; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria
- A view of the colonnaded street and site of Palmyra from the Palmyra Castle (Fakhr-al-Din al-Ma'ani) hill., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref49; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes
- Colonnaded street and Palmyra Castle (Fakhr-al-Din al-Ma'ani)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref50; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Forts/Castles
- Two people outside a building in a mountainous landscape in Syria or Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref51; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Men; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Syria; Iraq
- A view of valley in Syria or Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref52; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Syria; Iraq
- A group portrait of several women and men having a picnic in Syria or Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref53; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Picnic; Iraq; Syria; Alcohol; Drinks/Beverages; Hats; Guns; Weapons
- A river with brick structures at either side, most likely the Little Zab., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref54; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Little Zab River; Rivers; Bridges; Iraq; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills
- Two men in front of a fire at a campsite in Iraq or Syria (linked ref56,57,58)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref55; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Tents; Iraq; Guns; Weapons; Syria
- Two men smoking pipes in front of a fire at a campsite, with bottles of Tennent's Lager on the ground, in Iraq or Syria (linked ref55,57,58)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref56; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Smoking; Tobacco pipes; Drinks/Beverages; Alcohol; Food; Hats; Iraq; Syria
- Two men smoking in front of a fire at a campsite, with bottles of Tennent's Lager on the ground in Iraq or Syria (linked ref55,56,58)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref57; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Iraq; Tents; Smoking; Tobacco pipes; Alcohol; Drinks/Beverages; Hats; Clocks/Watches; Syria
- Two men in front of a fire at a campsite in Iraq or Syria (linked ref55,56,57)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref58; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Petroleum industry and trade.; Group Portraits; Smoking; Men; Outdoors; Iraq; Tents; Guns; Weapons; Syria
- A group portrait of men and women wearing paper hats and false noses (linked ref60)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref59; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Tuxedos; Costumes; Bow Ties; Facial Hair; Events/Occasions; Stoves/Ovens; Carpets/Rugs; Christmas; Lanterns/Lamps; Parties; Iraq
- A group portrait of men and women wearing paper hats and false noses (linked ref59)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref60; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Tuxedos; Facial Hair; Costumes; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Carpets/Rugs; Stoves/Ovens; Smoking; Tobacco pipes; Iraq; Events/Occasions; Parties; Christmas; Bow Ties
- A sign with 'See America First' handwritten on it. Most likely in Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref61; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Signs/Signposts; Deserts; Outdoors; Iraq
- A portrait of a dog standing beside a tent (Iraq or Syria)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref62; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dogs; Animals; Outdoors; Tents; Iraq; Syria
- Three group portraits of men and women posing beside an automobile that is parked in a crowded park/public garden, likely to be in the USA., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref63; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Men; Women; Hats; Crowds; Parks; Gardens; Group Portraits; Picnic; Unknown Locations
- A portrait of two men playing the banjo in front of a hammock., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref64; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; String Instruments; Musical Instruments; Outdoors; Unknown Locations; Banners
- A view of a waterfall., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref65; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Waterfalls; Water; Outdoors; Landscapes; Unknown Locations
- A group portrait of women, men and two children in front of a tent with two flags likely to be the Flag of the Kingdom of Iraq (left) and Flag of the Arab Kingdom of Syria (right)., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref66; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Boys; Children; Hats; Tents; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Girls; Flags; Cigarettes; Smoking; Iraq; Syria
- A group of several women and men outdoors, a man tries to balance a bottle on another man's stomach. A crate of Allsopp's beer is in the foreground. Taken in Iraq or Syria., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref67; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alcohol; Drinks/Beverages; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Cameras; Outdoors; Hats; Signs/Signposts; Picnic; Iraq; Syria
- Two portraits of men standing beside an automobile on a ferry. Most likely in Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref68; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Hats; Men; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Boats/Ships; Rivers; Water; Iraq
- The inside back cover of the album Baba Gurgur - First Oil Drilling in Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref69; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
- The back cover of the album Baba Gurgur - First Oil Drilling in Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref70; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
- A group portrait of several men surrounded by crates and equipment. Likely to be in the Kirkuk region, Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref71; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Hats; Uniforms; Regional/National Dress; Men; Workers; Postcards; Kirkuk Governorate, Iraq
- A portrait of a dog on a brick wall., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref72; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Postcards; Dogs; Animals; Unknown Locations
- Boats at Dinard where the The Rance meets the English Channel, with the Saint-Malo Cathedral in the background., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref73; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Postcards; Photographic Prints; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Flags; English Writing; Churches; Ille-et-Vilaine, Britany, France; Signatures
- A group portrait of three women and five men around a dining table., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref74; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Food; Alcohol; Drinks/Beverages; Smoking; Cigarettes; Tobacco pipes; Unknown Locations; Jewelry
- A portrait of two men on a boat. Most likely in Iraq., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref75; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Group Portraits; Iraq; Fishing
- A portrait of a woman wearing a coat with a fur collar., Circa 1927-1928; AD_MC_048_ref76; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_048)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photo Booth; Individual Portraits; Women; Fur Garments; Jewelry; Unknown Locations